VLADIK KHONONOV

SOFTWARE ARCHITECT, SPEAKER, AUTHOR, MENTOR

vladik@khononov.com +972-50-765-7534 @vladikk

Profile

I'm a software engineer with nearly 20 years of industry experience. During the years I worked for companies large and small, in roles ranging from Webmaster to Chief Architect.

I'm a regular speaker at leading software engineering conferences, such as O'Reilly Software Architecture, NDC, DDD Europe, and others. My topics include distributed systems, Domain-Driven Design, Microservices, Evolutionary Architecture, and software architecture in general.

As an author, I participated in the "Domain-Driven Design: The First 15 Years" book project, alongside Martin Fowler, Mel Conway, Rebecca Wirfs-Brock, and other industry leaders. Currently I'm working on a solo writing project for **O'Reilly**.

Proven Experience

Distributed systems design

Microservices, Event-Driven Architecture

Aligning software architecture with business needs

Domain-Driven Design, Event Storming, Evolutionary Architecture, Behavior-Driven Development

Evolving legacy codebases and recovering business domain knowledge

Event Storming, Evolutionary Architecture

Architectural patterns and approaches

CQRS, Event Sourcing, Hexagonal Architecture, Event-Driven Architecture, Test-Driven Development

Blog

<u>vladikk.com</u> - my blog on software architecture and other related topics

Education

The Open University of Israel

Dual Major, Management and Computer Sciences, 2011 (with distinction)

Experience

Invesus Group - Chief Architect (2017-Present)

In 2017 Internovus was merged with Invesus, and I was promoted to the Chief Architect position of the Invesus group (Internovus, Naxex, Tick Tech). At Invesus I'm in charge of mentoring junior and senior developers, evolving legacy codebases into Microservices and cloud based solutions (AWS), and providing architectural guidance for new projects.

Experience: Evolutionary Architecture, Microservices, Distributed Systems, TDD, Domain-Driven Design, Event-Driven Architecture, CQRS, Event Sourcing

Internovus - Chief Architect (2011-2017)

Internovus is a large scale online advertising and marketing company. As the first employee of the company I am in charge of both strategic and tactical software design and architecture.

At Internovus we've embraced AWS Cloud and Domain-Driven Design from the company's day one. We also employed state of the art technologies and architectural styles, such as Microservices, Serverless Computing, Event Sourcing, CQRS, Event-Driven Architecture, polyglot persistence, machine learning, and others.

In addition to my engineering duties, I built and managed international RND teams, mentored junior software developers and architects, and I'm in charge of research and technical guidance for RND teams.

At Internovus we always strove to deploy quality software, in aggressive times to market, keep the costs down, and all of this despite having very limited RND teams.

Experience: Evolutionary Architecture, Microservices, Distributed Systems, TDD, Domain-Driven Design, Event-Driven Architecture, CQRS, Event Sourcing, BDD

Malam Team - Senior Software Engineer (2005-2011)

Israel Air Force - Software and IT Engineer (2001-2005)

Beit Tochna Ve Makhshev - Web Developer (2000-2001)

Public Speaking

Microservices: The Advanced Basics (DDDx, MuCon London, KanDDDinsky)

7 Years of Domain-Driven Design (O'Reilly SACon, DDD Europe, NDC Sydney,

Code Europe, and more)

The Dark Side of Messaging (NDC Minnesota, MuCon London)

Polyglot Persistence via CQRS (Big Data Moscow)

Testing Software Architecture (TestCon Moscow)

How to Tame Test-Driven Development (TestCon Moscow, ISTA)

Full speaking profile: http://vladikk.com/page/speaking

Books and Publications

DDD: The First 15 Years

Publications
I participated in this book, alongside Martin Fowler, Mel Conway, Rebecca
Wirfs-Brock, and other industry leaders. In it I shared my 7 years long story
of implementing Domain-Driven Design and Microservices-based
architectures.

What is Domain-Driven Design? (WIP)

Devops: Exploring the Value of Microblogging, Cutter IT, Jan 2012

Languages

English - Fluent

Hebrew - Fluent

Russian - Mother tongue

Vladik Khononov — <u>vladik@khononov.com</u> — +972-50-765-7534